A Guide to the Papers of the Barney, Cooke, McClew and Neilson families, 1820-1905
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- I. LETTERS FROM CHARLES D. BARNEY TO LAURA E. COOKE
  - Charles D. Barney to Laura E. Cooke 1875 Aug 3
    Charles D. Barney & Co. Bankers and Brokers, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania: John, Harry; Julie Bullitt; invitation to a bachelor party
  - Charles D. Barney to Laura E. Cooke 1875 Aug 14
    Charles D. Barney & Co. Bankers and Brokers, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania: John, [Jay Cooke], Charlie Butler, Clara R[ ], Jay [Cooke, Jr.], Ned, and Eddie McGaw to Trenton for a new horse
  - Charles D. Barney to Laura E. Cooke n.d.
    --: death of dog "Jipprus"; [business] trip with John and James Bingham; Ella [Barney]'s health; [John W.] Sexton, W[illia]m [G. Moorhead]; and [Jay Cooke] at the office
- II. LETTERS FROM LAURA E. COOKE TO CHARLES BARNEY
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1866 July 29
    Long Island Sound, On board the Newport: destination Mr. Dodge's summer home, the "Farm," near Narragansett Beach, Rhode Island; describes the great confusion caused when the steamer collided with a scow; onboad with Sallie [Cooke] and parents [Jay and Dorothea Allen Cooke]; describes Mr. Dodge's house and surrounding area; loveliness of Ogontz; sailing on the ship; read Granville de Vigne and Strathmore[by Ouida] -- comments on them as horrid and wicked -- given Idalia as a gift
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1866 Oct 2
    --: on Put-In Bay Island, near Peach Orchard Point; discourse on her life's freedom from trial and tribulations; read John Greenleaf Whittier's "Mogg Megone"
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney [1866] Oct 10
    Erie, [Pennsylvania]: unhappy to be there, wanting to be home, missing Charles; parents like him but want them to be sure of themselves
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1866 Oct 15
    The Cedars: had her picture taken at Wenderoth & Taylor; comments on the "high spirits" of Charles D. Barney; Allie Porter; Jay B[utler]; Oliver Evans
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1866 Oct 17
    The Cedars: [John W.] Sexton; Jay [Cooke, Jr.], [Jay Cooke]; cousin Emily [Allen] reading Punchinello aloud to Harry; Sallie [Cooke] and [Dorothea Allen Cooke] playing backgammon; describes the library at the Cedars; read Charles Dickens' The Tale of Two Cities and David Copperfield
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1866 Oct 22
    The Cedars: Emma Allen of Kentucky; her kitten Gipsy; Oliver Evans; Barnaby Rudge; entered at Miss Carr's as a full scholar; matinee at the Academy of Music to hear [Verdi's] Trovatore; how glorious it is to be a Christian; Theo's return to St. Louis, Missouri; Jay Butler
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1866 Nov 18
    --: spent Saturday afternoon visiting by carriage driven by "George," the coachman; Anna Commerford, Dora, Aunt Sarah, and Sallie [Cooke]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Feb 3
    Brooklyn, New York: devastation over cancellation of Charlie's visit; church at St. Ann's in Brooklyn; Uncle Pitt [Cooke] recommendation to brother [ ] Cooke for Mr. Mills; Mr. Farr's sermon "Valley of Ach[ ] and taking charge of Grace Church; Lena Mills; William Bott; [Henry Ward] Beecher sermon in the evening. [Note: Henry Ward Beecher (1813-1887), clergyman, at Plymouth Congregational Church, Brooklyn, New York, 1847-1887]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Feb 10
    Ogontz: appreciation for a gift handcrafted by Charlie's sister and mother; discourse of love for each other; Cora Badger; [John Philip] Newman's sermon in evening; [Charles Edward] Cheney's sermon in morning; party at Mrs. Barlow Moorhead's with Lena Haddock, William Farr, and others; gift of little book Thoughts for Weary Hours -- quotes from book; Ella [Barney]. [Note: John Philip Newman (1826-1899), bishop; Charles Edward Cheney (1836-1916), rector of Christ Church, Chicago, Illinios]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Feb 17
    Ogontz: practicing in music room; festivities on Valentine's Day -- "Sandusky dance," Sandusky tunes by "eight piece & piano" band; Gertrude Farr, William Farr's sister; Dr. [Heman] Dyer's sermon in morning; Dr. Bancroft acceptance of a professorship in the Divinity School of West Philadelphia; death of her sister on February 19, 1865 -- Mrs. George Thomas; death of George Mears on February 1, 1866. [Note: Heman Dyer (1833-1900), clergyman, New York, New York]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Mar 18
    Ogontz: visit from Katie and Harry Howe of Germantown, [Ohio]; thirteen inches of snow; Mary Osborne's engagement; Louise's characteristics; sermons of Dr. Clayton and Mr. Tiffany of Germantown; Ginnie Thomas; went to church at Holy Trinity; Lena Haddock; going to visit relatives in Kentucky and then on to Sandusky, Ohio; Jay Butler
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 April 28
    Ogontz: returned from Washington, D. C. with Jay [Cooke]; description of excursion to the "Grand Falls"; visit by General [Ulysses S.] Grant's wife [Julia T. Dent Grant] and daughter; Mary Barber; Jay Butler; Kittie Campbell; Mary Patterson; "Cricket on the Hearth" rehearsals; Mrs. William Farr's reception with John Butler as fourth groomsman
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 May 9
    Kentucky Military Institute: Theo Hosmer; describes beautiful scenery of Kentucky; to travel to the Mammoth Cave; officers and cadets gentlemanly
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 May 12
    Kentucky Military Institute: uniforms remind of the old war; describes the actions involved in the inspection of students' rooms; attended one of the societies literary and debating; changed travel plans to the Mammoth Cave; cousin Sallie and Howard; comments on general activities at the institute; traveling to Sandusky, Ohio
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 June 18
    Gibraltar: discourse on their love and engagement; Fannie's funeral
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 July 7
    Ogontz: Cora Badger; George Thomas; Eva Bradley; Mr. and Mrs. Appleton, the new pastor and his wife; Rosa Birchett; Kittie [Campbell]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 July 26
    Brooklyn, New York: turning eighteen; Louise; Townsend; Sallie Mills; Caroline; visit to Narragansett, Rhode Island
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 July 31
    Echo Farm, Near Fall River, [Massachusetts]: ride in a three-seated wagon without a cover or backs to the seats; drive to Fall River; Mary Marchant; describes scenery on long drive towards Newport, Rhode Island and along the shores of Narragansett Bay, Rhode Island; going to spend the day on Mr. Dodge's yacht Silvie
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Aug 12
    Ogontz: servant Maggie Edmonson keeping her company while the family is away; plans to go to Willow Grove one evening; Ginnie and Richard Thomas; Tom and Charlie Parvin; [Jay Cooke] hiring Tom Parvin for a position in the office; discussion of books Frederick [the Great] and his Family and Frederick [the Great] and his Court
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Aug 25
    Mr. Bingham; Dorothea Allen Cooke, Jay Cooke, Jay Cooke, Jr.; rumor of Jay Butler and Ella Taylor engagement; slight feeling of depression
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Sep 1
    Ogontz: rumor of engagement of Vannie Durberrow; Mr. Appleton spoke at preparatory prayer meeting; Baptism of twelve children; Mr. Bingham and Dora's relationship; cousin Emily [Allen] and Nennie indisposed; John and Clara Horstman's relationship
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Sep 15
    Ogontz: Dora in Sandusky, Ohio; gentlemen visitors -- Uncle Harry [Henry David Cooke?], Uncle Pitt [Cooke], Mr. [James] Bingham, John Bingham, Uncle William [Moorhead], and Mr. White; description of the unusual Mr. White; going to Dr. Flagg the dentist; her cousin Emmie [Emily] Allen suffering from chronic rheumatism; Charlie's being appointed secretary at a meeting; Kate Farr, John Bingham, Mr. [James] Bingham, Jay [Cooke, Jr.], Dorothea Allen Cooke, and herself going to Sandusky, Ohio; Jay getting a director's car to go as far as Cleveland or Mansfield, Ohio
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Oct 1
    Gibraltar: croquet with Harry; cousin Emma [Emily Allen]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Oct 2
    Gibraltar: [Jay Cooke] and Mrs. McMeens playing backgammon
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Oct 7
    Gibraltar: Jay and Clara; Aunt Sarah [Cooke Moorhead], Dora, and Sallie Mills visiting
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Oct 9
    Gibraltar: fireworks night before; new books and supplies at Sunday School
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles E. Burney 1867 Oct 18
    Gibraltar: [Jay Cooke], Jay [Cooke, Jr.] and Hal Cooke fishing all day; going fishing and on a picnic to Middle Island; putting sample of cologne on cards to distribute to his mother and grandmother
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1867 Oct 19
    Gibraltar: Charlie's impending visit and arrival on the Star
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1867 Nov 14
    The Cedars: visit with Dorothea Allen Cooke to Aunt Sarah's [Cooke Moorhead]; Uncle William [Moorhead], [Jay Cooke], and Jay [Cooke, Jr.] away; "meteoric shower" previous night; visitors George Thomas, Anna Commerford, Caddie Moorhead, and Cora and Mary Badger; Ginnie Thomas, Jay [Cooke, Jr.], Joe Shoemaker, and herself watched meteor shower from the tower; description of Cora Badger; copy of a ballad "Under the Daisies!" [by Harrison Millard]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Mar 13
    St. Nicholas: comments on his letter of March 11th; Dorothea Allen Cooke, Aunt Lizzie, Clara, and Jay [Cooke, Jr.]; returning to Ogontz by train
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Mar 30
    Ogontz: visit by Miss Rubeau; took lesson at the school from Miss Merino; [Jay Cooke]; practice on her harp; describes beautiful sunset; Sallie [Cooke] at Ginnie Thomas' house; Tom [Parvin] and [Jay Cooke] playing billiards; visit by Ms. Lozier to treat her father's [Jay Cooke] carbuncle on his face
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Apr 1
    Ogontz: her wedding present to Charlie -- solid silver-gold lined sauce boat for $36.00 from Caldwell's; reading The Pillar of Fire; [or, Israel in Bondage] by [Joseph Holt Ingraham]; going to Dr. Flagg, the dentist, with John and Nennie; Ella's [Barney] health
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Apr 3
    Ogontz: sewing at Mrs. Thomas' for the Fair with Nennie, Sallie [Cooke], Mrs. Appleton, Cassie Brock, and Cornelia Grayson; her parents [Jay Cooke] and [Dorothea Allen Cooke], Mr. Appleton, Joe Shoemaker, Mrs. And Mrs. George C. Thomas, Mr. Thomas, Dr. Clayton and his daughter, Mrs. Aubin, and Tom Parvin arrived; plans for tomorrow include fair work, school work, harp lesson, and prayer meeting; Ella's [Barney] health
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Apr 4
    Ogontz: practice at the church with Jay [Cooke, Jr.]; Sunday School, sermon on the origin of "Confirmation"; group giving a concert Tuesday; Clarke family visiting; baptism and confirmation; Ella's [Barney] health
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Apr 6
    Ogontz: rode on new train on the North Penn[sylvania] with Nennie and [Jay Cooke] to the city; stopped at the office and met John [Butler?], [John W.] Sexton, and Tom Parvin; went to Van Harlingen's; visited Clara Horstmann; includes pen-and-ink sketch of self; cousin Emily [Allen]; Christina Dodge
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Apr 7
    Ogontz: confirmation of eighteen by Bishop [Alfred] Lee of Delaware; Ella's [Barney] improved health; anticipation awaiting the visit of Charlie. [Note: Alfred Lee (1807-1887), the Episcopal Bishop of Delaware]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 May 27
    Williamsport, [Pennsylvania]: her feelings following her departure
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 [May ?]
    Biddle House, Detroit, Michigan: dirty hotel slight improvement over Russel House; Aunt Cora and Carrie
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 May 31
    Detroit, Michigan: attended St. Paul's Church and heard an unusual sermon; hard day's journey from Niagara on two sections of the "Pullman's Palace Hotel Cars" which were comfortable; Jay [Cooke, Jr.], Sallie [Cooke], Cassie, and cousin Emily [Allen]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 June 1
    Gibraltar: left Detroit, Michigan in the morning, on the way down the Detroit River, stopped on board the Jay Cooke, a large steamer; arrival of [Jay Cooke], [Dorothea Allen] Cooke, Harry and Mary
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 June 2
    Gibraltar: going to St. Paul's and Lake Superior with papa [Jay Cooke] and mamma [Dorothea Allen Cooke]; illness of Ella [Barney] and Charlie's mother; comments on [ ] Kemble ? [Harriet McEwen Kimball] and a book on Lady Jane Grey and Mary Stuart; Jay Butler; cousin Emily [Allen]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 June 3
    Sandusky, Ohio: visit to Charlie's mother, Sallie [Barney?], Aunt Martha, and his grandmother; Ella [Barney] and her severe illness; saw "Drummer Boy!" at Norman Hall
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 June 17
    Gibraltar: cousin Emily [Allen], Mrs. Appleton, Sallie, Clara, Cassie into lake for a swim; Ella's [Barney] illness; engagement of Richard and Clara H[orstmann]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Aug 8
    Ogontz: dancing party at Aunt Sarah's [Cooke Moorhead]; Sallie [Cooke], Emily [Allen], and [Dorothea Allen Cooke] going to Cape May, New Jersey
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Aug 10
    Congress Hall: describes travel and accommodations; sending a birthday gift of sleeve studs
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Aug 11
    Cape May, New Jersey: visitors Clara Reeves and Carrol Tyson; her love for him; Clara and Katie Sagers; bathing in the slightly strong surf; Mary Edward having rooms in the "Blue Pig"; steriopticon exhibition on the lawn
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Aug 12
    Cape Island, New Jersey: tea with Mrs. E. W. Clarke at her cottage; having a "Hop" in the dining room; Mrs. Clarence Clarke; taking a walk with Sallie [Cooke] up the beach and back by the Columbia House; playing "Champagne Charlie" for a gallop at the "Hop"; attending Episcopl services with Sallie; Heber Newton and family coming
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Aug 13
    Cape May, New Jersey: describes the "loveliest view of the sea"; bath with no surf as the tide was very low -- good for swimming and floating; going for a drive on the beach; Ginnie Rowland and Jay [Cooke, Jr.]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Aug 20
    Congress Hall: children's hop tonight to be unusually pretty; Mr. Evans; concern over Charlie's illness; others gone to Tenpin Alley; ate delicious pears, peaches, nectarines, and sugar plums; higher tide and more surf for bath; evening activities include riding and playing croquet
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Aug 22
    Cape May, New Jersey: describes view of the Atlantic Ocean from her porch; [Jay Cooke] and Mr. Bingham out fishing; reproachful of Charlie's Sunday activities
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Sep 23
    Williamsport, Pennsylvania: met Joe S[hoemaker] at Quacake Junction; Mrs. Moorhead and Carrie; cousin Emily [Allen], Sallie, and Mary Patterson; Harry and Joe Shoemaker; Dorothea Allen Cooke, Aunt Cora, and herself in same rooms; sadness at his departure; copied some of her "Serving Children's" names in her book; Mr. Powell's wedding; fantasies about her own wedding; Great Western Railway Company ticket
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Sep 23
    Pullman Hotel Cars between Elmira and Rochester, New York: describes scenery from Williamsport, Pennsylvania, along Seneca Lake; news of the presidential competition between [Ulysses S.] Grant and [Horatio] Seymour; quotes Hiwatha; arrival at Congress Hall, Rochester, and waiting to leave for Niagara
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Sep 25
    Pullman Hotel Cars: left Niagara and passing through Canada all day; pamphlet for Pullman's Hotel Car Great Central Route
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Sep 26
    Onboard the Jay Cooke: enroute to Gibraltar on the Detroit River; discusses the Jay Cooke as a new steamer on the line
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Sep 27
    Gibraltar: discussion of wedding plans; spent last evening engaged with fancy-work, etc.; excellent sermon by Mr. Weldon; her love for him; [Jay Cooke] and Will Moorhead to arrive following day
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Sep 28
    Gibraltar: arrival of the General Lyon with [Jay Cooke], cousin Will Moorhead], John Butler, and James Bingham; men then went on a hunting expedition to Middle Island and Point au Pillee; playing croquet; making a black silk cravat for him
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Sep 29
    Gibraltar: playing croquet; hearing Charles Dickens' prettiest "Christmas Stories"; describes view of the Lake and Middle Bass Island; Charlie [Charles B.] Dennis
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Sep 30
    Gibraltar: Will [Moorhead] reading Dickens aloud; Will, Aunt Cora, cousin Emily [Allen], and herself went rowing and had a game of tenpins swung on a gate; John left for Sandusky, Ohio on the Jay Cooke; playing game of croquet; [Jay Cooke] and Will [Moorhead] are fishing; Sallie Mills
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 1
    Gibraltar: Mamma [Dorothea Allen Cooke] and Papa [Jay Cooke] postponing her trip to Sandusky, Ohio; General Butler and the Trustees of Soldier's Homecoming; wanting Sallie [Barney] to visit; cold and blustery, white caps in the bay; Mamma and Papa out fishing; Aunt Lizzie and Aunt Cora on a rowing expedition, stranded on Squaw Harbor; the County Fair; comments on Charles being at the Cedars; death of little Maggie Fahnestock and of her own little sister Carrie at the same age
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 2
    Gibraltar: row of four miles to the "West Dock" and back; [Jay Cooke] and Will [Moorhead] fishing all day; [Dorothea Allen Cooke], Aunt Lizzie [Moorhead], and cousin Emily [Allen] started out in the Piscatoribus Sacrum; Aunt Cora, Sallie, and Carrie [Moorhead] also in their boats in the bay; Aunt Cora reading aloud Charles Dickens' Golden Mary, "a pitiful story of shipwreck & danger at sea"; discusses characteristics of Carrie Moorhead; relationship between Mrs. Barney and Dr. Keiffer
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 4
    Sandusky, Ohio: hearing the church bells before going to church; Sallie [Barney]; comments on the choir which included Mrs. Frank Moss, soprano, Georgie Moss, alto, and a fine tenor and bass; Mr. Farr's sermon; discussion with Mrs. Barney on the matter of Dr. Keiffer and the future; went to the fair-grounds and saw some fine racing [horses or dogs?]; describes Dr. Keiffer's physical appearance and his mannerisms; going to church with John Butler; comments on Dr. Keiffer and his intentions toward Mrs. Barney
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 5
    Sandusky, Ohio: going home in Evening Star; Sallie Mills; others' positive comments on the new minister [Dr. Keiffer]; John Butler giving a dance on Wednesday night
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 6
    Gibraltar: fishing all day with cousin Emily [Allen], Aunt Lizzie Moorhead, Nennie, Mrs. McMeens, and Aunt Mary; dinner on Middle Island, carried by the revenue cutter Sherman; [Jay Cooke] received word that General [John Henry] Martindale (1815-1881) and his daughter and Governor Smythe and his wife are visiting; Sallie Barney
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 7
    Gibraltar: Mrs. McMeen's bad disposition; activities including sewing, singing and playing piano; [Jay Cooke] and Will [Moorhead] on tug to the peninsula to shoot squirrels; their marriage in the spring; Fannie Osborne, Leiscester Hubbard, and George Hubbard [incomplete]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 8
    Gibraltar: Miss Martindale, Major DeKay (General Butler's secretary), Mrs. Smythe, General Butler, General [John Henry] Martindale, and Governor Smythe arrived on the Jay Cooke from Detroit, Michigan; [Dorothea Allen Cooke], Mr. Gunkill [Lewis B. Gunckel (1826-1903)] of Dayton, Ohio, and Judge [Hugh Lenox] Bond (1828-1893) of Baltimore, Maryland arrived on the Evening Star; comments on some of the guests; plans to go to Europe in the spring
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 10 a.m.
    --: planning for their wedding to be in the spring; [Mrs. Barney] and Sallie
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 10 p.m.
    Sandusky, Ohio: at cousin Caroline's for dinner; Mrs. Barney; riding; wearing new black silk dress; improvement of cousin Jay [Butler]; kittens deserted by mother having to be drowned; church in morning, excellent sermon from Mr. Farr; Mary Barber in choir again; Dr. Keiffer preaching in evening; her new room at Ogontz
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 12
    Sandusky, Ohio: visitors [Jay Cooke], [Dorothea Allen Cooke], cousins Will [Moorhead], Emily, and Harry; [Jay Cooke] and Will [Moorhead] going to "Club house" for duck shooting; berating Charlie at length for "kissing promiscuously" in the light of their relationship
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 13
    Sandusky, Ohio: their love for each other, their relationship, and their engagement and upcoming marriage; played a game of "Authors": a [Republican] procession with fine transparencies and a splendid band of music; Mrs. Barney; Dr. Keiffer; going to Detroit, Michigan in the Jay Cooke; party for children at Aunt Mary's
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 13
    Sandusky, Ohio: Sallie [Barney] returning to Gibraltar with her; visited Mrs. Barney, Sallie [Barney] and Aunt Martha
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 15
    Gibraltar: playing croquet, rowing, playing the piano; festival for the benefit of the church attended by [Jay Cooke], [Dorothea Allen Cooke], Uncle William, Will [Moorhead], Kennedy Moorhead, and herself
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1868 Oct 16
    Gibraltar: Sallie B[arney] roasting chestnuts with Sallie [Cooke]; playing croquet; rowing -- describes the scenery on the lake and relates a story of the wind and rain disrupting the taking of a photograph of everyone in their boats; [Jay Cooke] and Kennedy Moorhead on fishing excursion; leaving for Detroit, Michigan on the Jay Cooke; Mrs. McMeens and Durham having plans for a "fete champetre" on the lower end of the [Put-In-Bay] Island; played games of "Pussy wants a corner" and "Proverbs"
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868] Oct 23
    --: feeling blue over their not being together; going to a concert to hear among others Madam Pareba, who is said to sing as well as Jenny Lind, and Mr. N. B. Mills, a celebrated performer
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1868 Nov ?]
    --: rejoicing in the streets over the election [of Ulysses S. Grant and Schuyler Colfax as president and vice-president]
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney 1872 Sep 25
    Sandusky, Ohio: left O. Y. R. Station for Elmira, New York, in the drawing room car accompanied by John, Sallie, Clara, Minnie Parvin, and Mr. Bingham to Bethlehem, Pennsylvania; describes travel; their children, Dolly and [ ] with her; death of Burton Spencer's wife following childbirth; Lollie Mills gravely ill
  - Laura E. Cooke to Charles D. Barney [1872] Sep 28